Siddharth Joshi . Jarvis Consulting

Hello! I'm Siddharth Joshi, a Software Engineer with a Bachelor of Technology in Computer Engineering from Charusat University. My journey with technology began with small passion projects like a 2D survival game in the Godot Game Engine in University. I later contributed to a project that revamped the software in the University's hospital's blood donation department, discovering the impactful potential of technology, which further fueled my passion for it. I am proficient in Java, Python and Relational Databases. I gained valuable teamwork experience at ABXR Engine, a startup dominating in Augmented Reality industry. I'm confident in bringing both technical expertise and value to your organization.

Skills

Proficient: Java, Python, RDBMS/SQL, Linux/Bash, Agile/Scrum, Git Competent: Django, C/C++, JavaScript, Flask, Godot Game Engine Familiar: C#, .NET Framework, Amazon Web Services, NoSQL, Docker

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis data eng SiddharthJoshi

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: A Monitoring Agent intended for the Jarvis Linux Cluster Administrator Team (LCA). This project gathers the real-time data from all the available machines such as hardware specifications (CPU, Memory, etc.). This data is persisted in a relational database providing accurate records of data at a particular timestamp. This data will be used by the LCA team to manage resources. This project can be deployed across multiple host machines to enable real time data gathering. The technologies used for this project are Postgres Database, Docker, Git, GitHub and Linux.

Core Java Apps [GitHub]:

- Grep App: This project is a robust simulation of the Grep Command Line Tool in Linux. It is implemented in Core Java utilizing Maven for seamless build management along with Docker for deployment. Users can input a regex pattern, select a starting directory for the search, and designate an output file. This empowers the tool to generate a comprehensive list of matched lines, ready for further analysis.
- Stock Quote App: This Application is a Personal Stock Wallet that allows users to effortlessly buy, sell, and track all their stocks in one place. This acts as a central repository for all the company stocks utilizing PostgreSQL via JDBC. This app is portable across all platforms.

Highlighted Projects

Cheap Flight Finder [GitHub]: This Project is a prototype designed for people who want real time updates of price drop in flight tickets. This Project is implemented in Python and its associated libraries. This Project runs on command line and sends real time alerts via email whenever flights prices are low. It is really handy for me as I can get updates on price drops / low prices instead of checking everytime. Further enhancements in this project are yet to be made.

Blood Bank Data Management System: In this project, I worked in developing a highly efficient full-stack application for the university hospital, utilizing HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, MySQL, JavaScript, and PHP. The old legacy system of the blood donation department reeked of bugs and errors along with inconsistencies. This project enhanced the older system serving as a replacement with refined UI, robust database and smooth navigation. As a result, blood donation department operated more smoothly than before thus enhancing patient care and quality service to the patients.

Professional Experiences

Software Engineer, Jarvis Consulting Group (Nov 2023 - Present): Leveraged multiple cutting-edge technologies to build multiple projects spanning in various fields of software.

Software Engineer, ABXR Engine (Aug 2023 - Dec 2023): In ABXR Engine which is a no-code platform, people can create AR content which they can play once published within minutes leveraging wide array of in-built tools. One of them being adding AI-generated voice to the characters and scenes. I was working on designing and implementing RESTful APIs which would generate AI-based text-to-voice enabling the users to generate and play a variety of different voices including famous celebrity voices. To store the voices so they are saved with the content, AWS S3 bucket was leveraged along with Python which would store the voices on cloud from the backend.

Education

Charotar University of Science and Technology (2018-2022), Bachelor of Technology, U & P U Patel Department of Computer Engineering - GPA: 3.5/4.0

Miscellaneous

- Sports: I love playing team sports such as basketball, cricket, tennis, table tennis, volleyball. I'm also into swimming, marathons, yoga, etc.
- Hiking: Hiking and camping makes me feel connected with nature which I truly enjoy and appreciate.
- Volunteering: Contributing to society always motivates me. One time from my university, I was volunteering for providing basic necessities to people in rural areas.
- Reading: Reading novels and books gives me peace. I truly enjoy exploring different genres such as Magical Realism, etc.
- Travelling: Perhaps one of the best things, I love to travel and explore the world, getting to know different people and their cultures along with exploring the unknown.